Contact

+7-9213882934 (Mobile) samehome@yandex.ru

www.linkedin.com/in/alesavin (LinkedIn) alesavin.ru (Personal)

Top Skills

Hosting Services
SaaS
Java

Languages

Russian (Native or Bilingual) English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Machine Learning
Principles of Reactive Programming
Big Data Analysis with Scala and
Spark

Теория игр (Game Theory)
Functional Programming Principles in Scala

Alex Savin

Lead Software Engineer at EPAM Systems Andalusia

Summary

More than 10 years of experience at software development: started from DevOps role to team leader. I joined Yandex. Classifieds infrastructure (Saint Petersburg, Russia) in 2011, my core points there were: Java/Scala development, highload architectures, distributed systems for big data/stream processing (Hadoop/Kafka/Spark), search and near topics. At the start of 2019, I relocated to Malaga, Spain, initially in favor of Ciklum project with a strong passion for functional programming and now I have a warm welcome at EPAM with wider opportunities. I like to build high-quality systems according to The Reactive Manifesto and invest in coaching others to make wonderful things together.

Experience

EPAM Systems Lead Software Engineer January 2020 - Present (8 months) Málaga Area, Spain

Ciklum

Senior Scala Developer February 2019 - January 2020 (1 year)

Málaga Area, Spain

My project was related to gambling area. I developed event-based microservices for sport-betting industry at small team with platform duties. Mostly DDD, reactive and functional programming.

Yandex

7 years 10 months

Senior Software Developer Team Lead November 2015 - January 2019 (3 years 3 months) Saint Petersburg, Russian Federation

I lead group of developers with designing, developing and support backend for quality and commercial platforms, deal with software tasks at infrastructure

Page 1 of 3

team of vertical searches business unit. Prefer reactive programming patterns and Scala/Akka technology stack.

Software Developer

April 2011 - December 2015 (4 years 9 months)

Saint Petersburg, Russian Federation

Developing Java, Scala services for vertical search on car ads, vacancies and realty offers. In details: 2-4 mln entities depends on service, >1000 partner feeds, fault-tolerant ETL (extract, transform, load) process include feed downloading, data sharding, unification, clusterization, index building, index update on 64 search machines. Hadoop/HBase for statistical tasks, MySQL for analytics. Team share tasks on services for the best replaceability.

Figures: full index update over 15 min, fast search 4000rps 99.9% < 50ms, detailed search 500rps 99% < 500ms.

Technologies: Scala/Akka/Spray, Lucene, Cassandra, HBase, MySQL.

Favor-IT

5 years 2 months

DevOps

April 2008 - April 2011 (3 years 1 month)

Developing, managing and deploying software for water analysis. Full process from workspace organization to production release: infrastructure tasks (VCS/IDE, CI, fault- tolerant network, phone support system, monitoring), hardware selection and installation (common/blade servers, RAID, SuSE linux, network), software development (Java EE, EJB, Servlets, JSP), deploy (self-developed system), product support. Lead (include hiring) personnel of infrastructure group (2 people max).

Technologies: Linux, Java EE, Tomcat, PostgreSQL, Ant.

System Engineer

March 2006 - March 2008 (2 years 1 month)

Managing server farm for the SaaS solution (water analisys). Figures: 2 data centers, >60 machines, >20 services (10-100 users each), SuSE Linux, RAID, fault-tolerant network. Manage emergency switch to slave services or backups (1h outage max).

BizHost

System Engineer

July 2005 - December 2005 (6 months)

Web hosting, mail hosting. FreeBSB- based virtual hosting with self-developed panel (PHP, MySQL), dedicated hosting. Figures: >10000 sites, 10 machines.

Education

Saint Petersburg State Polytechnical University

Master of Science, Computer Science · (2005 - 2006)

Saint Petersburg State Polytechnical University Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (1999 - 2004)